Guide to the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, UPG Senate, 1970-present UPG.RG.35
ULS Greensburg
- Subject Files, 1971-2006; VII.
  - Planning Policies for the 1980's, University, 43.
    - Planning Policies for the 1980's, University (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Presidential Task Force on Assessment, 11/20/2001; 44.
    - Presidential Task Force on Assessment, 11/20/2001 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Public Service Evaluation, 1987; 45.
    Contains a memorandum from C.F. Poke dtd 9/17/87, subject, "Guidelines for the Evaluation of Public Service".
    - Public Service Evaluation, 1987 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Recruitment, Student, 1975-1982; 46.
    Contains: Position Paper, "Minority Recruiting for Greensburg Campus" [1975?]; memorandum from Larry J. Whatule to Kenneth Wenger dtd 1/8/76, subject, "Recruitment of Minority Students"; Report to UPG Affirmative Action Committee dtd 2/20/76 in re recruiting; report 4/7/76, subject, "Findings/recommendations concerning 1) staff hiring, 2) faculty hiring, 3) student admissions, and 4) housing lists with regard to possible discrimination" from the Affirmative Action Committee; guidelines (1977), "Affirmative Action Policy for Recruitment, Selection and Advancement of Personnel at the University of Pittsburgh" on the Greensburg Campus; memorandum from Larry J. Whatule to Greensburg Senate dtd 12/12/77, subject, "Affirmative Action Report: Student Recruiting"; Affirmative Action Report for 1981-82.
    - Recruitment, Student, 1975-1982 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Regional Campus Report, 1976-1979; 47.
    Contains minutes of UPG Senate meeting of 11/29/79 at which Assoc. Provost Nossen spoke on the proposed closing of the Titusville campus and the future of UPG.
    Research Development Fund (1977-78)
    UPG Senate minutes of 3/1/76 contains item, "Scholarly Research and the Greensburg Campus" with Stanley Katzman, discussion leader.
    - Regional Campus Report, 1976-1979 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Salaries, UPG Faculty, 02/22/1985; 48.
    - Salaries, UPG Faculty, 02/22/1985 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Secretarial Problem, 1975; 49.
    - Secretarial Problem, 1975 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Snyder Amendment, 1972; 50.
    - Snyder Amendment, 1975 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Staff (Non-Faculty) Matters, 1975-1978; 51.
    Subjects include: minority recruitment; procedures in recruiting; staff hiring; a proposed motion (undtd) to the UPG Senate in re a staff salary scale, staff promotion, annual written job evaluations.
    - Staff (Non-Faculty) Matters, 1975-1978 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Student Activities Center, 1975-1976; 52.
    - Student Activities Center, 1975-1976 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Student Board of Conduct, 1979; 53.
    - Student Board of Conduct, 1979 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Third Term Employment, 1973-1978; 54.
    Contains: copy of proposed resolution dtd 1/17/73 to Senate Council concerning third term teaching; minutes of UPG Senate 3/8/73 which contain Appendix 2, A nine point plan proposed by the Faculty Welfare Committee in re third term employment; memorandum dtd 2/17/78 from Carl F. Poke to All Full-Time Faculty, subject, "Teaching Loads and Compensation for Over-Loads and Third Term Teaching"; resolution dtd 3/7/78 from the Faculty Welfare Committee titled, "Resolution on Administration Proposals in Regard to Overloads, Third Term Teaching and Basic Overloads"; minutes of UPG Senate 4/4/78 which contain a report on responses to an opinion poll by Carl F. Poke in re "Third term guideline"; memorandum dtd 4/5/78 from Carl F. Poke to All Full-Time Faculty, subject, "Report on Faculty Response to Polling of March 14, 1978."
    - Third Term Employment, 1973-1978 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Traffic on Campus, 1979; 55.
    - Traffic on Campus, 1979 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - UPG President Search Committee, 1980; 56.
    - UPG President Search Committee, 1980 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Upper Division Proposal (UPG), 1974; 57.
    - Upper Division Proposal (UPG), 1974 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
  - Urban Management Program, 1975; 58.
    - Urban Management Program, 1975 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 5)
- University of Pittsburgh, Oakland Senate, 1970-2015; VIII.
  - By-laws, 1971-1999; 1.
    (Edition, Jan., 1971; Edition, Apr., 1971; Proposed Revisions, 1998; Proposal For Revised Senate By Laws, 1999; Proposed Revisions, undtd)
    - By-laws, 1971-1999 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Minutes, agendas, etc., 1970-2011; 2.
    Numerous gaps. Mainly agendas, lists of standing committees, necrology; some minutes. [Extract from University Times April 28, 2011] Senate Plenary Session [April 14, 2011]: Teaching excellence & tenure. 13 p.
    - Minutes, agendas, etc., 1970-2011 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Minutes (Council), 1970-1974; 3.
    Numerous gaps. Mainly agendas, rosters of members of council.
    - Minutes (Council), 1970-1974 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Athletic Committee, 1975; 4.
    Annual Report, June 30, 1975.
    - Athletic Committee, 1975 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Budget Policy Committee, 1977; 5.
    - Budget Policy Committee, 1977 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
      Minutes, 12/2/77.
  - Educational Policies Committee, 1971-1974; 6.
    Contains: Report, "On the University Senate, Governance and Educational Policy at the University of Pittsburgh", Dec. 8, 1971; motion by various faculty members, "that the Senate adopt the recommendations of the Educational Policies Committee as expressed in the 12/8/71 report; 1974 evaluation of the Report of the Tenure Commission by the Educational Policies Committee.
    - Educational Policies Committee, 1971-1974 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Elections, Committee on, 1971-1979; 7.
    Ballot for 1971-72. Call for nominees for Standing Committees (1979); undtd report on nominees for office [Senate] and for Faculty assembly.
    - Elections, Committee on, 1971-1979 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Library Committee, Senate, 1975; 8.
    Memorandum 10/31/75 from the Senate Library Committee to Senate Council in re "Salaries in the University of Pittsburgh Libraries"; memorandum 11/12/75 from Wesley W. Posvar to VC Jack Freeman, Provost Rhothen Smith, VC Joseph Dutton, subject, "Library Study".
    - Library Committee, Senate, 1975 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Nominating Committee, 1972; 9.
    Guidelines for the Nominating Committee (1972).
    - Nominating Committee, 1972 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Nontenure Stream [NTS] Faculty Issues, Ad Hoc Committee on, 2015; 10.
    "Final Report for Presentation at Faculty Assembly on Feb. 10, 2015".
    - Nontenure Stream [NTS] Faculty Issues, Ad Hoc Committee on, 2015 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Nontenure Stream Faculty subcommittee of the Gender Discrimination Initiatives subcommittee of the Senate Anti-Discrimination Policy Committee, 2012; 11.
    Report [Recommendations for Senate Council [from] Subcommittee on Full Time NTS Faculty, November 27, 2012].
    - Nontenure Stream Faculty subcommittee of the Gender Discrimination Initiatives subcommittee of the Senate Anti-Discrimination Policy Committee, 2012 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Organization and Procedures Committee, 1975; 12.
    Proposal to Change the Way in Which Senate By-laws May Be Amended (Distributed for first reading), 5/8/75.
    - Organization and Procedures Committee, 1975 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Tenure and Academic Freedom Committee, 1974-1988; 13.
    Evaluation of the Tenure Commission Report (5/13/74); Report (1987/88) of the committee; position paper on tenure from the Tenure Committee, Pitt Professional Union; Position Paper on the Role of Teaching by N. Austern, (undtd).
    - Tenure and Academic Freedom Committee, 1974-1988 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - University Governance, Ad Hoc Committee on, (Oakland), 1974-1975; 14.
    Annual Report, 1974/75.
    - University Governance, Ad Hoc Committee on, (Oakland), 1974-1975 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Women's Center, Ad Hoc Committee for a, (Oakland), 1969-1988; 15.
    Proposal for the Establishment of a University Women's Center (1972).
    Annual Reports. 1969/70; 1974/75; 1976/77; 1980/81; 1983/84; 1984/85; 1987/88.
    - Women's Center, Ad Hoc Committee for a, (Oakland), 1969-1988 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
  - Subject File, 1974-2006; 16.
    Subjects include: Parliamentary Procedure (1974)
    Part-Time Faculty (Resolution on Part-Time Faculty, 1975)
    Registration/Student Records (Resolution, 1972)
    Senate Staffing (Paper, "Staffing the Work of the Senate of the University of Pittsburgh: A Discussion and Suggested Directions" (1971)
    Student Government (Oakland) (undtd report, "Issues On Which Student Government Is Presently Working")
    Reorganization/Termination of Academic Programs ("University Policies Relating to Reorganization or Termination of Academic Programs (11-3-80)
    Planning and Resource Management System University of Pittsburgh (Nov., 1980)
    ltr 10/12/05 from Irene H. Frieze, Pres., University Senate, in which IHF provides information on the University Senate and Faculty Assembly and invites faculty participation in those forums for representing faculty opinion in an ongoing dialogue with administrators, students and staff. Ltr includes list of members of the Faculty Assembly including elected representatives of the Faculty Assembly, Chairs, co-chairs of Senate Standing Committees, dates of 2005/06 Faculty Assembly and Senate Council Meetings.
    - Subject File, 1974-2006 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)
- University of Pittsburgh, Oakland Faculty Assembly, 1977-1998; IX.
  Minutes, agendas, etc. [1977/78-1993/94] Minutes only for 1993/94; mainly agendas, lists of members of Faculty Assembly.
  Documents. Report of the Faculty Assembly On the Status of Faculty Appointments, University of Pittsburgh. April, 1998. 21 p.
  - University of Pittsburgh, Oakland Faculty Assembly, 1977-1998 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 6)